A Guide to the Holland family Records, 1833-1902
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
Holland family Records, 1833-1902
Library of Virginia
21573a
1.85 cu. ft. (7 boxes and 1 volume on shelf)
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open to research.
Acquisition Information
Purchased.
Biographical/Historical Information
The Holland family resided in Franklin County, Virginia. Asa Holland (1801-1879) was a prominent merchant and farmer in Franklin County, Virginia. His daughter Sallie Elizabeth Holland (1835-1920) married William Erastus Duncan (1825-1912) of Amherst County, Virginia. Asa Holland operated general stores in Halesford in partnership with John D. Booth, and in Germantown in partnership with Smithson H. Holland.
Scope and Content
Records, 1833-1902, of the Holland family of Franklin County, Virginia. Includes day books, invoice books, journals, and ledgers relating to the operation of general stores of the Holland family in Halesford and Germantown (1835-1844). Includes information on other accounts of Asa Holland (1833-1837; 1843-1845; 1900-1902) and his son Mark D. Holland (1870-1879). Also includes advertising items, bills, a draft of a deed of trust, and receipts (1835-1879), as well as a list of magazine subscribers (1854-1859).
Contents List
- Account book, 1833-1902 (Box 1)
  Account book of Asa Holland
- Invoice book and journal, 1835-1847 (Box 1)
  Asa Holland and John Booth general store at Halesford, Franklin County, Virginia.
- Journal, 1835-1837 (Box 2)
- Ledger, 1833-1844 (Box 3)
  Asa Holland and Smithson H. Holland accounts for shoes, boots, and other leather goods. Store location unknown.
- Journal, 1841-1844 (Box 3)
- Daybook, 1841-1842 (Box 3)
  Asa Holland and Smithson H. Holland general store store at Germantown, Franklin County, Virginia.
- Ledger, 1840-1841 (Box 4)
  Asa Holland and John Booth general store. Location is unknown.
- Journal, 1840-1841 (Box 5)
  Asa Holland and Smithson H. Holland general store at Germantown, Franklin County, Virginia.
- Daybook, 1841-1843 (Box 6)
  Asa Holland and Smithson H. Holland general store. Location is unknown.
- Journal, 1842-1843 (Box 7)
  Asa Holland and Smithson H. Holland general store at Halesford, Franklin County, Virginia.
- Account book, 1843-1859 (Box 7)
  Asa Holland general store. Location is unknown.
- Daybook, 1850-1857 (Box 7)
  Executions received by Asa Holland, Franklin County, Virginia. Also includes diary entries of William E. Duncan, schoolmaster in Franklin County, Virginia.
- Account book, 1870-1879 (Box 7)
  Asa Holland and Mark D. Holland general store. Location is unknown.
- Loose papers, 1835-1879 (Box 7)
- Ledger, nd (Volume On shelf)
  Blank ledger.